ALETI KRISHNA CHANDRA MOULI

Mobile: 6305056304 Email: krishnachandramouli5@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishna-aleti/ GitHub: https://github.com/KrsnaAleti
Address: SCB:1-03-136, Jaya Nagar Colony, Near 7 temples, New Bowenpally, Secunderabad, TS - 500011

ABOUT

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Python, Databases, Python Frame works, Circuit design in robotics, Machine Learning, PoCs development, Microsoft Office, Public Speaking and Engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) focused in Electronics and Communications Engineering from Aditya Institute of Technology and Management. Pursuing Data Science Masters Certification from PWSkills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Senior Software Engineer at ValueLabs

09/2022 - Present

- o Project: e-Com site, PoC Development, Role: Analyst.
- Worked for the inhouse LLM based tool AiDE, Analysis and worked on AiDE Existing features development/New features implementation, feedback system.
- Worked with the prompt engineering team for better inputs and increasing the accuracy of the output.
- Developed Text scanner function (to scan for potential PHI) as part of AiDE-development.
- Analyzed the AI/ML solution for a prospect in construction.
- o Completed the front end dashboard design for EV charging management.
- Prepared test cases utilizing comprehensive business requirements, functional documentation.
- Worked as scrum master, run daily standup calls to ensure there are no impediments and prepare MOM and share with Engineering Manager. Perform Sanity, regression testing on daily basis.
- Create tasks in Jira for the functionality tested along with details like FTR's, story points, Log bugs in IIRA Tool and assign it to the respective service developer
- Check for the logs in Splunk (it uses an application programming interface (API) to connect to applications and devices).
- o Create and maintain WiKi pages in JIRA targeting zero redundancy and zero obselete tests.
- Received multiple client appreciations and internal appreciations Star of the Month for Feb-2023, Aug-2023.
- Technologies/Tools Used: JIRA, Postman, Manual testing, Automation testing, API testing, Jmeter, PoC Development, Python, Machine Learning, Prompt engineering.
- Systems Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services

06/2020 - 09/2022

- Business flows: B2B and B2C, Role: Analyst.
- Real-time analysis of Electric vehicles, Charging stations, and their integration with the Central system.
- Process improvisation: Developed a python based tool for the automatic upload of test cases into JIRA from the excel book increasing the efficiency and reducing the manual efforts.
- Worked with the internal portal team for developing/implementing new features for ideas evaluation using NLP. A part of the freshers training team.
- Requirements analysis and tasks management. Working with various JIRA reports after analysis for the client reporting.
- Complete flow validation from Portal to CRM and billing validation in Zuora. Mobile application analysis and validation of data with the related platforms.
- Integration check and API validation among various platforms.
- Algorithms validation for the Electric vehicles. Entire system integration check.
- Handling the JIRA issues/bugs, tracking and reporting the same to the stakeholders. UAT support for different regions (Italy, Spain, Chile, Romania, USA) of the world.
- o Technologies/Tools Used: Python, NLP, Jira, Emulators, CRM, Zuora, Postman, Swagger.

• Assistant Systems Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services

- 12/2019 06/2020
- o Project: Anti Money Laundering (POC Robotics and Cognitive Systems), Role: Python Developer.
- o Analysis of the requirement and designing of the required tools.
- As per the requirement, fetching all the information and analyze them.
- Developed a tool to extract and analyze the company details. Extracted the line of business as per the analysis.
- o Technologies/Tools used: Python 3.7, Selenium, Natural Language Processing.
- Assistant Systems Engineer Trainee at Tata Consultancy Services

05/2019 - 12/2019

- SAP & DAP, Role: Manual Tester.
- Complete End to End testing of Novelis businesses which comprises of various modules like SAP Material Management, Plant Maintenance.
- o Designed queries to validate the information from multiple platforms.
- o Data Migration testing among Hive, Source, Landing platforms.
- Testing all the migrated data using SQL. Analyzing the data using PowerBI, Informatica MDM. Reporting defects, tracking them and reporting the same to the stakeholders. Testing, Analyzing, defect management during the execution times working with the client.
- o Technologies/Tools Used: Hive, PowerBI, Informatica, MDM, SAP, SQL

SKILLS

- C language
- Python
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Cassandra
- Python Libraries: pandas, NumPy
- Python Frameworks: Django, Flask
- Machine Learning
- Prompt Engineering
- API Development REST API, Fast API
- Manual Testing, API Testing
- CRM, Zuora

INTERNSHIP

• Data Science Intern at iNeuron.ai

07/2021 - Present

• Python Intern at iNeuron.ai

02/2021 - 07/2021

- o Python for Data Science (unpaid)
- o Credentials: https://academy.ineuron.ai/certificates/downloads/PY099890.pdf
- Intern at Electronics Corporation of India Limited

04/2018 - 05/2018

Secured International Data Encryption Algorithm development

EDUCATION DETAILS

• Graduation 2019

- Aditya Institute of Technology and Management
- B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering CGPA: 8.77/10

• Intermediate Education 2015

o Sri Chaitanya Junior College - 97.7%

o Minerva Model school - CGPA: 9.8/10

PoC & PERSONAL PROJECTS

• Password Leak Check

- o Objective: To check the strength of our passwords.
- o Designed 2 versions of the tool Check multiple passwords at a time, check one password at a time.
- It gives a chance to the user to enter another password if the previous password is found in the list of hacked passwords.
- If the user wants to discontinue, he/she can simply enter "STOP" when it is prompted to Enter a new password. Once "STOP" is entered the program will be terminated.
- o GitHub Link: https://github.com/KrishAleti/PwdLeakCheck

• Automation of test cases upload in JIRA using Python

- Objective: To Automate the process of uploading the test cases present in all the Sheets of the Excel book. This reduces the manual efforts of copying and pasting the testcases step by step into JIRA.
- o IDE/Tools Used: Selenium, Python.

• Wireless notice board using voice commands (Final year Project)

- Objective: To display notices/messages without typing them manually.
- We come across situations where we need to display notices/messages on a screen urgently.
- Here we propose an innovative arduino based notice display system.
- This system is capable of displaying the voice messages and the some pre-defined messages.

• Secured International Data Encryption Algorithm (Internship Project)

- Objective: VLSI implementation of the IDEA block cipher using VHDL
- Data security is an important issue in computer networks and cryptographic algorithms are essential parts in network security.
- Our chip contains the eight units, and each unit can execute one round of the algorithm.
- Our implementation operating at 10 MHz achieves a throughput of greater than 700 Mbps, which is several times higher than previous implementations.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp by Udemy
- Introduction to the MongoDB by Udemy
- Data Analyst by Udemy
- Complete Python Developer in 2021: Zero to Mastery by Udemy.
- Python for Data Science by iNeuron.ai.
- o Python Data Structures by Coursera: University of Michigan.
- o Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) by Coursera: University of Michigan.

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

- Attended IEEE SENSORS-2018 and published a paper(IEEE jedzx-1475).
- o IEAE Student Project of the Year 2018 award for the project titled "Advanced Smart Car."
- IEAE Student Project of the Year 2018 award for the project titled "Design of Compact Aerosol Sensor by using Integrated Spectropolarimeter using Photonic Integrated Circuits".
- Published Academic Research Paper in IJETSR journal at 2nd International Conference on New Frontiers of Engineering, Science, Management and Humanities (ICNFESMH-2018).
- Got remarkable position for the designed robot in "Electrothon" a state level competition organised by Andhra Pradesh Information Technology Academy.
- Stood 2nd in district level "Innovative Science Exhibition".

ACTIVITIES

- Participated in the "Research Expo" conducted by Indian Institute of Technology-Madras.
- o Presented a paper on Earth quake detection in NIT-Warangal.
- Participated in "Entrepreneurship Awareness Camp(EAC)" organised by Andhra Pradesh productivity Council in association with Entrepreneurship Development Institute of India.
- Worked as President of Student Activities Centre Technology Incubation Hub at AITAM-Tekkali, managed many clubs out of which Robotics club had major contribution and conducted/participated in technical fests.
- Worked as Electronics department coordinator in Aditya Institute of Technology and Management.
- o Mentor for Talent transformation under the domain of Basic Electrical & Electronics.